Did Google just ruin the best AI image
generation model for e-commerce? Okay,
let's try this out here. Loading Nano
Banana 2. Okay, didn't get a choice. Not
even that much faster so far. Okay, but
we got these little three buttons here.
Redo with Pro. Okay. All right. So, at
least we still have the Pro option.
Let's see what that does.
Nani?
>> What the
That is not better.
It's literally just the exact same photo
that I took with some Canva things on
top of it. Wow, so bad. So bad, dude.
Okay, let's see what's going on here.
Nano Banana 2. Is Nano Banana 2 the best
AI image generator yet? What?
Nano Banana 2 just changed the way I
create. Insane. The new generative AI
image generator is insane, insane.
Google's Nano Banana 2 is crazy, crazy,
crazy bad. Nano Banana 2 insane, insane.
They're all saying insane, insane. I'm
insane. I'm going insane because I don't
either I'm smoking crack
or all of these YouTubers are sponsored
by Google or both because Nano Banana 2
is not better. Nano Banana 2 is worse by
a large margin. It's way worse. Google
Nano Banana 2 is incredible.
Incredible. Incredible? Dude, who are
these people? Who are these people? How
is it It's incredible. It is incredible.
It's incredibly bad. Dude, I don't I
don't know if there's some kind of
cabal, some kind of like conspiracy that
I was never invited to or a secret
society or if all of these people are
just sponsored by Google or what it is,
but I
I just don't understand For some reason,
I'm the only one who sees that this
model is a huge downgrade from Nano
Banana Pro. A huge downgrade. And not
only is it a downgrade, but Google has
now locked you into it. You now can't
use Nano Banana Pro on your first prompt
using the Gemini app. It forces you to
use Nano Banana 2. And what I'm going to
do in this video is I'm going to break
down for you guys actually what's going
on with this AI image generation update
and why you're kind of
because Google just made it impossible
for you to use Nano Banana Pro on the
first prompt using the Gemini app. And
this really was revolutionizing for
brand owners and e-commerce business
owners because it's the first time that
we could actually generate images that
are way better than professional product
photography and professional design that
you would normally pay hundreds or even
thousands for for your Amazon listing.
It was completely game-changing. Still
is completely game-changing, but Gemini
just downgraded the model. And now, no
matter what model you use, Fast Thinking
Pro, it is going to use Nano Banana 2,
the inferior model. And specifically for
product photos and e-commerce images,
very inferior, highly inferior, and
nowhere near the quality of Pro. Now,
there is a way around this. I'm going to
walk through it in this video, but you
still can use Nano Banana Pro in chat,
but you can't do it with the Gemini app
anymore. I'm going to show you how to do
that without any third-party apps or
anything like that. I don't have any
sponsors for this channel. I literally
have no one telling me, and I don't know
if that's what's happening with these
YouTube channels and these other guys
and stuff that I'm seeing.
I don't I don't know if they're just not
really testing it out or if they're not
testing it for e-commerce or what, but I
seem to be the only person actually
telling the truth about this huge
downgrade on this model that's far, far
worse than the best model that we have,
which is Nano Banana Pro, and that we
just got locked out of. But there is a
way around it. There is a way to still
use Nano Banana Pro to come up with
listing images that are professional,
highly designed images just like you
would pay hundreds or thousands of
dollars for. I'm going to walk through
the new way to do this in this video.
But first, let me show you what I mean.
So, check this out. I'm in the Gemini
app and just so you know, I have the
Ultra plan. This is the biggest possible
[music] plan that you can have. So, it's
like $130 a month
and you get a huge amount of credits to
generate images. You don't need this
plan to access Nano Banana Pro, but you
do need one of the paid plans. So,
there's Pro and then there's Ultra. I
have Ultra because I'm a super power
user, but you don't need that plan. You
can just take the Pro plan. So, the way
it used to work is on your screen, you
had fast thinking and Pro. If you hit
fast, it would use the original Nano
Banana model and if you hit thinking or
Pro, it would use Nano Banana Pro, the
advanced model that generates realistic
[music]
photography and perfectly designed
images with text and everything ready to
upload to Amazon or your e-commerce
listing. Now, all three models use Nano
Banana 2, which Google says is an
upgrade from Nano Banana 1 and I would
agree with that. It's definitely an
upgrade from Nano Banana 1, but it is a
huge downgrade from Nano Banana Pro and
there is now no way [music]
to generate a Nano Banana Pro image from
the Gemini app or even from the Gemini
web app. The only way to get a Pro image
now is to first generate a Nano Banana 2
image and then hit the three dots on
that image and click regenerate with
Nano Banana Pro. Now, the problem with
this is, as you can see from the example
that we're walking through here, that
Nano Banana 2 has inferior context
recognition. So, it's going to generate
an image that doesn't understand the
context as well as Pro would from the
get-go. So, the image is bad. Like in
this case, you can see it's the wrong
color. This
photo
clearly shows at least some color
gradient, right? Now, I know the
lighting's not great in this, but you
can tell that there's a color gradient.
The the
actual product is dark blue fading to
black at the top, but Nano Banana 2 did
not pick up on that. I guarantee Nano
Banana Pro would have. So, it made the
whole thing black.
And my only option is to regenerate that
bad image that's already bad using Nano
Banana Pro. The problem is the original
image had faulty logic on it because
Nano Banana 2 is not as good at picking
up context clues and generating a
realistic image and generating the image
that you actually want. So, what this
means is you if you effectively simply
just can't use Nano Banana Pro anymore
using the Gemini app. It is blocked from
you. The only thing you can do is
generate inferior images with Nano
Banana 2
>> [music]
>> and then regenerate those bad images
with Nano Banana Pro. It makes zero
sense. It is so frustrating and I do not
get why no one is talking about this.
So, this is a problem, right?
At first, you're like, "Wow,
they literally just took away a
superpower that I had to generate
high-quality Amazon listing upload-ready
images to my e-commerce listing and to
my Amazon listing for all my products.
But there is a workaround and you don't
need any third-party tools for this. You
just need to use Google's AI image
generation model from a different
platform called Google AI Studio. So, to
do this, just go to aistudio.google.com.
And here, you're going to go to
playground and then what's going to
happen is it's going to ask you to input
an API key. Now, you do need one of the
paid plans plus or pro or ultra in order
to do it this way and there's a couple
more steps at first but once you get it
set up you can actually use it the same
way that you're used to using Nana
Banana Pro if you've watched any of my
other videos. So, what you have to do to
set this up is you have to go to get API
key down here then you just click create
API key. You'll see this API key here.
Then once you go back to the playground
it's going to ask you to select which
API key you want to use. You select the
one you just created and then you can
start using Nana Banana Pro. Now, what
you'll see is that it's default still to
Nana Banana 2 but over here on the right
you can click that switch down to Nana
Banana Pro
and now you can start using Nana Banana
Pro the way you normally would. The only
thing that's kind of annoying about this
is that you can't just take pictures
with your phone and quickly chat back
and forth and then take another picture
if that reference image wasn't good. You
have to take the pictures with your
phone or your camera then
upload them to your laptop through
Google Drive or whatever, send them to
yourself, then you can upload them here
using this little plus. And this way you
can continue making high quality
professional grade Amazon listing images
for your e-commerce and your Amazon
listing using Nana Banana Pro which is
what I would recommend you do. Nana
Banana 2 is really not that bad. I know
I'm on it a lot in this video
but it's really not terrible. You can
get some
pretty good images out of it if you
don't make it do anything crazy like a
lot
like it's
not as good at graphics for sure. The
primary image sometimes it gets right.
The thing is I don't I don't I really
don't understand why everyone's freaking
out. It is faster slightly not even by
much. It's like a couple seconds faster,
but it's so significantly worse. It's
just The logic is just I just don't get
it. Like I
>> [laughter]
>> When I was watching videos on this,
I was like, "Am I cra- Am I crazy? Am I
the crazy one here?"
I really And I still don't know because
I don't
I just don't get it. I don't know. Maybe
I just Hey, Google, if you're giving all
these people sponsorships, don't leave
your boy out, right? At least I mean, I
won't take it because I don't take any
sponsorships. This channel is not
sponsored. It's only sponsored by me.
But I still want the offer, bro. I don't
want to be left out. If everyone on
YouTube's getting sponsored, hey, your
boy's feeling a little left out here.
Now, for a step-by-step on how to use
Nano Banana Pro to actually generate,
including what prompts to use, how to
converse back and forth with it, click
the link in the description of this
video, and I would click it now because
the video keeps playing while you
download it. It's not going to interrupt
your video at all. Just click it now.
You can download it while you're still
listening to me talking, and it'll come
back to the video without interruption.
So, click that, and you'll download a
full guide of how to use Nano Banana Pro
to generate Amazon listing images. And
I'm updating the guide with these new
updates for how to do it now after this
Gemini update and after this image
generation update because I still
recommend not to use Nano Banana 2. Use
Nano Banana Pro. There's really no good
reason to use Nano Banana 2 if you're
serious about creating really good
Amazon listing images. The only The only
reason I could think of is if you're
like trying to quickly come up with
ideas or quickly iterate cuz it Yeah,
it's a couple seconds faster, not even
by much. So, maybe if you're like really
impatient, you have crazy ADD or ADHD.
Otherwise, there's really just no reason
to do this. You want to use Nano Banana
Pro, and you have to do it the way that
I said. There are other ways to do this,
too. You can use Higgs Field or these
third-party apps. I'm not sponsored by
any of those guys. Everything that I'm
telling you is completely based on my
own experience. So, nobody is paying me,
nobody is sponsoring me.
This is the most direct way that I like
to use it right in Google AI Studio,
just using Google's own AI platform, but
just not through Gemini. Because for
whatever reason, they have now locked us
out completely, no matter what plan
you're on, from using Nano Banana Pro
from the get-go. All you can do is
generate Nano Banana 2 images, and then
regenerate those bad images with Nano
Banana Pro, which completely defeats the
point in the first place. Call me crazy.
I don't know. Maybe I'm having a
different experience than everybody
else. Fine. That's what I'm observing,
and that's what we're doing internally
at my company, Sophie Society. And if
you sell on Amazon, and you are
interested in partnering with a company
who's at the leading edge of how to grow
brands on Amazon profitably, reach out
to me. I want to talk to you. Just click
the website sophiesociety.com in the
description of this video, fill out the
little form to contact me, and I want to
chat with you about how we can work
together to accelerate the growth and
profitability of your brand using
all of the cutting-edge strategies, but
also specifically using Amazon Ads and
Amazon PPC strategies, which is what
this channel is primarily about. If you
want to see how to use Nano Banana Pro
step-by-step in another video, you can
watch this video here, where I walk
step-by-step exactly what prompts I use,
and exactly what conversation I use with
the model, and you can apply it now.
It's just the difference is, instead of
in Gemini, you're going to have the
conversation in Google AI Studio. But, I
go through step-by-step exactly how to
create a full Amazon listing image set,
including main image, secondary images,
lifestyle images, benefits graphic,
features graphic, instructionals
graphic, step-by-step, all of that. And
it's all detailed in this video here.
So, check that video out here now and I
will see you over there.